(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-09T22:28:42.962205",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
MUSIC GARDEN - TAKANE LUI Birthday 2025
[Title: MUSIC GARDEN - TAKANE LUI Birthday 2025]
尾丸ポルカです よろしくお願いします
I'm Omaru Polka! Glad to be here!
こんばんは 司会の白上フブキです よろしくお願いします
Good evening! I'm your host, Shirakami Fubuki! Pleased to be here!
さて 今夜も始まりました MUSIC GARDENでございますけれども
Now then, tonight marks another edition of MUSIC GARDEN, but...
なんか 久々だね
It's been quite a while, hasn't it?
はい 約2年ぶりに...
Yes! Returning after about two years...
そういうことでですね
So, with that said...
復活... めでたいね
The revival... It's worth celebrating, isn't it?
そうですね！
Indeed!
髪切った？
Did you cut your hair?
あ、切ってないんですけども 2年前もそんなこと言ってましたね
Ah, I didn't cut it, though! You said the same thing two years ago too.
そうだっけ？
Was that so?
そうですよ！ ポルカさんもお変わりなく
Yes, it was! Polka-san hasn't changed either.
まぁ、はい。元気でやってるよ
Well, yes. I'm doing well!
それは良かったです！ ポルカさんの元気にも負けないくらい、今回元気なゲストさんもいますので！
That's good to hear! And we have energetic guests today who match even Polka-san's energy!
うん、それは楽しみだね
Yeah, I'm looking forward to that.
はい！では早速紹介していきましょうか！
Yes! Shall we introduce them right away?
本日のゲストの登場です！
Here come today's guests!
音乃瀬奏
[Guest: Otonose Kanade]
猫又おかゆ
[Guest: Nekomata Okayu]
大神ミオ
[Guest: Ookami Mio]
百鬼あやめ
[Guest: Nakiri Ayame]
鷹嶺ルイ
[Guest: Takane Lui]
今夜も豪華ゲストでお送りするミュージックガーデン！
Music Garden is brought to you with lavish guests tonight!
なんと今夜は、あっ！と驚くような仕掛けいっぱでお送りするみたいですよ！
Remarkably, tonight will be filled with surprising tricks and gimmicks!
最後まで見逃せません！
You can't miss a single moment until the very end!
あー...どんな仕掛けなんだろうねぇ
Ah... I wonder what kind of tricks those are.
えー、鷹嶺ルイ君
Um, Takane Lui-kun?
はい！
Yes!
ミュージックガーデンと言えばまぁ鷹嶺ルイ君だから 今日は誕生日ということで
When we think of Music Garden, it's Takane Lui-kun, and today is your birthday.
はい！ありがとうございます！そうなんですよ、今日誕生日なんですよ！
Yes! Thank you very much! That's right, today is my birthday!
うわー、2年ぶりに復活したけど...どう？緊張してる？
Wow, it revived after two years... How is it? Are you nervous?
はい、緊張してます！でも復活にふさわしい場にできるんじゃないかなと思っているので、楽しみにしていてください！
Yes, I'm nervous! But I think we can make this a stage worthy of this revival, so please look forward to it!
かつ、これなんか匂いますね
Plus, I smell something coming up...
え？ちゃんと、お風呂入ってきた...
Eh? But I took a bath properly...
その匂いじゃない(笑) 違いますね、それじゃないですよ！
Not that kind of smell! No, that's not what I meant!
あ、そうかそうか。今日は一曲目の披露だよね
Ah, I see, I see. Today you're revealing the first song, right?
はい、このあとすぐに披露させていただきます！
Yes, I will perform it right after this!
はい！一曲目は鷹嶺ルイさんに、アニメの主題歌でも話題でした「BOW AND ARROW」を披露していただきます！
Yes! For the first song, Takane Lui-san will perform "BOW AND ARROW", which was a hot topic as an anime theme song!
ほう、あのフィギュアスケートの...
Oh, that figure skating one...
はい！今回は特別にフィギュアスケート風のダンスを踊ってくださるダンサーさんと一緒にパフォーマンスさせていただきます！
Yes! This time, I will perform together with dancers who will perform figure skating-style dance!
おー！それは楽しみだなぁ！
Ooh! That's something to look forward to!
そうですね！それではスタンバイの方、よろしくお願いします！
Indeed! Well then, please get ready for standby!
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes, thank you very much!
ね、あれ...猫又君と音乃瀬君と大神君...あ、初登場だっけ？
Hey, by the way... Nekomata-kun, Otonose-kun, and Ookami-kun... Ah, is it their first appearance?
そうですねー！
That's right!
うーん、音乃瀬君、緊張してるんじゃない？
Hmm, isn't Otonose-kun nervous?
もう全然大丈夫ですよ！イケまーす！
I'm totally fine! I can do this!
元気だねー！ブレないよー！
So energetic! She doesn't hesitate!
そして2回目の登場が百鬼君
And appearing for the second time is Nakiri-kun.
はい、お久しぶりですー！
Yes, long time no see!
今日はシュークリーム食べた？
Did you eat cream puffs today?
いや、ちょっと今日はまだ...まだ今日は食べてないです
Well, today not yet... I haven't eaten any today yet.
あ、そうかそうか。後でね、ゆっくりね、食べてね
Ah, I see, I see. Eat plenty later at your leisure, okay?
はい、いっぱい食べます！
Yes, I'll eat lots!
後ほど皆さんともゆっくりお話しさせていただこうと思います
Later, we'll talk with everyone at leisure as well!
さて、スタンバイができたみたいですね！
Now then, it looks like standby is ready!
アニメをリスペクトしたダンスにもご注目ください！
Please pay attention to the dance respecting the anime!
鷹嶺ルイで「BOW AND ARROW」！
Here is Takane Lui with "BOW AND ARROW"!
気づけば靴は汚れ 錆びついた諸刃を伝う雨
Before I knew it, my shoes were worn, rain tracing the rusted edge of a double blade
憧れはそのままで 夢から目覚めた先には夢
Holding on to pure admiration, I woke from one dream, only to find another waiting
聞こえたその泣き声 消える手前の咽ぶソフレ
I heard that trembling cry, a sobbing silhouette on the verge of vanishing
憧れのその先へ 蹲る君を見つける為
Beyond the longing lies the answer, to find you there, curled up and waiting
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で 飛べ インパルス加速して
Go, go, with a speed no one can catch! Fly, let impulse drive you faster!
Go, go! At an unreachable speed, fly! Accelerate the impulse!
行け きっとこの時を感じる為に生まれてきたんだ
Go! I was surely born to feel this exact moment!
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて 額に吹き刺す風
Grasp the future, exceed expectations, wind piercing my forehead.
今に見なよ きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just you watch, everyone will surely notice your brilliance!
相応しい声で 視線追い越して 虚空を超えて行け
With a worthy voice, overtake their gaze, soar beyond the void!
見違えていく君の指から今 手を放す
I now let go of your transforming hand.
気づけば謎は解かれ 木目ごと見慣れた板の上
Before I knew it, the mystery solved, on the familiar wooden stage.
あの頃焦がれたような大人になれたかな
I wonder if I've become the adult I longed to be back then.
そう君の苦悩は君が自分で選んだ痛みだ
Yes, your suffering is the pain you chose for yourself.
そして掴んだあの煌めきも全て君のものだ
And that sparkle you grasped is entirely yours as well.
僕は弓になって 君の白んだ掌をとって強く引いた
I became a bow, took your pale palm, and pulled back hard.
今君は決して風に流れない矢になって
Now you become an arrow that will never be blown by the wind.
行け 行け 決して振り向かないで 飛べ もう届かない場所へ
Go, go! Never look back! Fly to a place no one can reach!
行け 行け 行け 君はいいつだって輝いていた！
Go, go, go! You were always shining bright!
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて 額に吹き刺す風
Grasp the future, exceed expectations, wind piercing my forehead.
今に見なよ きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just you watch, everyone will surely notice your brilliance!
相応しい声で 視線追い越して 虚空を超えて行け
With a worthy voice, overtake their gaze, soar beyond the void!
見違えていく君の指から今 手を放す
I now let go of your transforming hand.
はい 続いては「ねこたか」です
Alright, up next is Nekotaka!
よろしくお願いします！
Great to be here!
2人はどういう関係なの？
What kind of relationship do you two have?
パーティ仲間で…
Party companions...
パーティ？
A party?
よくルイの家で勝手にパーティ開催してます
We often throw parties at Lui's place without asking.
勝手に？！
Without asking?!
ああ なかなか仲が良くてですね 人の家で勝手にパーティはしないと思うんですけどもね
Ah, well, you must be really close. Though usually people don't throw parties uninvited.
ねー
Right?
いやいや そうなんですけど 最初私もすごい驚いたんですが 最近ではもう私から「次いつパーティ？」っていうくらいにはトリコになっちゃってますね
No, no, that's true, but at first I was really surprised too. Lately though, I'm so hooked that I even ask when the next party is!
ああー…
Ah...
これ 猫又くんの策略かな？
Is this Nekomata-kun's strategy?
こうなると思ってました！
I knew it would end up like this!
思ってたんだ！
You knew it!
ポルさんたちも今度どうですか パーティ？
How about you guys join us next time for a party, Pol-san?
パーティっていうのは…私が行ってもいいのかな？
A party, huh... Is it really okay for me to go?
ぜひぜひ！
By all means!
あ やっぱり猫又くんが許可出すんだね
Ah, so Nekomata-kun is the one giving permission after all.
あー 楽しそうですねー！
Ah, sounds like fun!
ポルさんもぜひ！
You should definitely come too, Pol-san!
あ じゃあ この後ででも行きましょうか ポルさん ね？
Ah, then shall we go right after this broadcast, Pol-san?
ほら ほら… 鷹嶺くんが苦笑いしてるんですけど… 勝手に決められちゃいましたね
Look, look... Takane-kun is giving a strained smile... It was decided without asking her.
そんな2人にはですね かっこよさが詰まったダークチックな曲をお披露目していただきます！
So for these two, they will be performing a dark, cool song packed with style!
闇堕ちしてるじゃないか！
Aren't you falling into darkness?!
そうなんですよ
That's right.
でもね ねこたかならではの低音を生かしたかっこいいパフォーマンスをしますので 楽しみにしててくださーい！
But we'll be giving a cool performance utilizing Nekotaka's signature low tones, so please look forward to it!
はーい！
Yeah!
それではスタンバイ お願いしまーす！
Alright then, please get on standby!
はい よろしくお願いします！
Sure, thank you!
いやぁ 仲が良そうでいいですねー！
Man, it's so nice seeing them get along so well!
まぁぶっちゃけあれは 鷹嶺くんもまんざらでもなさそうだよね
Well to be frank, Takane-kun doesn't seem to mind it at all either.
うん そうですねー なんか我々もパーティに混ざっていいみたいですし
Yeah, true. And it sounds like we're welcome to join the party too.
ルイさんの作るポテトサラダが絶品らしいのでねー！
I heard the potato salad made by Lui-san is exquisite, after all!
なんか詳しいね？
You're surprisingly well-informed?
まあまあまあ… ということでスタンバイができたみたいですね！
Well, anyway... It looks like they're ready on standby now!
なんか隠し事か？
Are you hiding something?
いやいやいや！ それでは参りましょう！ねこたかで、『フィクサー』！
No, no, no! Well then, let's get started! Nekotaka performing "Fixer"!
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
I can't sleep until all my memories up to today are erased.
あしたから生きていく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I desperately want a substitute for myself to keep living tomorrow.
大丈夫と言わせて 後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Let me say "It's fine," then can't you let me blame you later?
今更意味ないから後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Is it pointless now to let me blame you later?
出来ない約束をとうとうと溢れる一言一言ばかりに脳を奪われるくらい
My mind is so consumed by every single overflowing word of promises that can't be kept
意味を成さない 何も出来ない
Making no sense, unable to do anything
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らせない
Can't see, want to run, want to fly, want to quit, can't look away
だから
So
沈め 沈め 這い上がれないほどまで
Sink, sink, to the point where you can't crawl back up
飽きるまで 落とせ
Drag it down until you get sick of it
救い垂らす時まで
Until the moment help is offered
嘘味の粒々を喉から締め出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Crushing lie-flavored grains along with the screams forced out of the throat
笑顔が下手なばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
Being terrible at smiling, I just get by conforming to a know-it-all tone
なりたくなかった
I didn't want to become like this
今日役立つ眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by useful, sleepy, sleepy ideals today
一番目は「い」の口で言う
Speak the first part with an 'I' shaped mouth
力強く硬く痛く噛み締めて
Clenching hard, firmly, and painfully
死んでしまえ
Just drop dead
この先も過去も知らず 嫌いなら
Knowing neither the future nor past, if you hate it
壊せ
Destroy it
どうせなら加害者になればいい
If anything, you might as well become the perpetrator
食べきれない苛立ちも何も生まない悲しみも
Unbearable frustration and unproductive sadness too
味気なくて吐き出す前にもう もう次を歌え
Before throwing it up tasteless, now, sing the next line
沈め 沈め
Sink, sink
落とせ 落とせ
Drop it down, drop it down
どうせなら踊り踊れ 灰色になり切る前に 打ち鳴らせ
If anything, dance and dance, strike a beat before turning completely grey
変われ
Change
眠り落ちる時まで
Until the moment you fall asleep
どうせなら奪え
If anything, snatch it away
飼い慣らした嘘暴いて
Exposing tamed lies
煮え滾る頭に過ぎった虚像を見ていた
I was looking at a phantom passing through a boiling head
自分を見ていた
I was looking at myself
続いてはルイなでのお二人です
Next up, we have the duo "LuiNaDe"!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
元気がいいなー
So energetic!
また言ってる
You're saying that again.
2人は先輩と後輩なんだよね？
You two are senior and junior, right?
はい！
Yes!
よく話すの？
Do you talk often?
はい、よくご飯に行ったりしてます
Yes, we often go out to eat together.
お、ご飯！いいですね
Oh, meals! That's nice.
何食べるの？
What do you eat?
主にしゃぶしゃぶですかね
Mostly shabu-shabu, I'd say!
あー！しゃぶしゃぶかー！
Ah, shabu-shabu!
一つの鍋をつつく関係、これいいですね
Sharing a single hot pot, that's a nice closeness.
実はですね、ポルさんに相談がありまして
Actually, I have something to consult Pol-san about!
お？相談？
Oh? A consultation?
ルイ先輩はいつまで経ってもね、奏のお母さんにはなってくれないんですよ！
Lui-senpai won't become Kanade's mom no matter how much time passes!
言ってやってくださいよ！
Please tell her!
お母さんにしてほしいんだ？
You want her to be your mom?
奏はいつだって優しいお母さんになってくださる方々を募集してます！よろしくお願いします！
Kanade is always recruiting anyone who will be a gentle mother to me! Please!
え、なんでお母さんになってあげないの？逆に
Wait, why won't you become her mom? On the contrary.
いや、なんかな…奏は娘って感じがしないというか…
Well, somehow... Kanade doesn't really feel like a "daughter"...
娘になったら手がかかりすぎて、ちょっと責任が持てないなーって感じなので、親戚ポジションでいいかなって感じです
If she became my daughter, she'd require too much care and I can't take that responsibility, so a relative position is fine.
壮大だな！
That's quite something!
音乃瀬くんはじゃあ、他にもママがいるの？
Otonose-kun, do you have other mamas then?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
じゃあいらないでしょ！何で欲しいの？
Then you don't need another! Why do you want one?
それはね、頼れる人はいっぱいいた方がいいじゃないですか！
Well, isn't it better to have as many people to rely on as possible?!
じゃあ逆にポルさん、奏のお父さんになってくれませんか？
Then on the flip side, Pol-san, won't you become Kanade's father?
え？お父さん？
Huh? Father?
お父さん？
Father?
どうですか？
How about it?
その意見は通さんって言ってるの！
I'm telling you I won't approve ("tou-san") that opinion!
ルイなでにはこの後、「名前のない怪物」を披露していただきます！
Next up, LuiNaDe will perform "Namae no Nai Kaibutsu" for us!
え？なんでこの曲選...
Eh? Why did you pick this song...?
すぐいけるんだ そうやって
You can jump right into it like that.
私があですね EGOISTが大好きで
I really love EGOIST, and...
その中でもこの曲がすごい大好きなんですけど
among their songs, I especially love this one.
わための初めての歌ってみたがこの曲で
Watame's very first cover song video was this one,
いつか一緒に歌いたいなと思って この曲にしました
so I chose it hoping we could sing it together someday.
それではですね お二人ともスタンバイお願いします
Well then, please get on standby, you two!
はーい よろしくお願いします
Okay! Thank you!
なんかはちゃめちゃな曲だね
What a crazy song, isn't it?
よく月曜日に現実を突きつけたりしてるみたいですよ
She seems to often slap people with reality on Mondays.
あー 罪深い
Ah, how sinful...
クソガキだ
What a brat.
しかし歌で見せてくれるので ギャップ萌えしてる人も多いんじゃないかなと思います
But since she shows her talent through singing, I bet many are charmed by the gap.
鷹嶺君も歌はかっこいいのに なんかポンコツだからね
Takane-kun is cool when singing too, but she's kinda clumsy otherwise.
ギャップがある二人って感じがいいんじゃないでしょうかね
Isn't it great that both of them have that gap?
はい それでは参りましょう ルイわためで「名前のない怪物」
Alright then, let's get started! LuiWatame with "Nameless Monster".
名前のない怪物
[Nameless Monster]
御伽話は
The fairy tale...
さっき死んだみたい
seems to have died just now.
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
In this brick hospital ward, unable to sing well.
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
In the foggy night, floating a red moon.
ほらみて 私を
Look at me...
目を逸らさないで
Don't look away.
黒い鉄格子のなかで 私は生まれてきたんだ
Behind these black iron bars, I was born into this world.
悪意の代償を願い 望むがままにお前に
Wishing for the price of malice, as you desire, to you...
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して壊される前に
Come, let us bestow justice, before destroying and being destroyed.
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Paying the price of karma, let's go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing.
鉄条網うるさくって
The barbed wire is making so much noise.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody of that day.
雨はまだ止まない
The rain still hasn't stopped.
何にも見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
Look, it has grown so big.
黒い雨降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Rain down black rain from this sky, I am an unwanted existence.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurotic, to the beloved bystanders who share the guilt...
さあ今震える正義を
Come, now, with a trembling justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて この身体を受け入れ
embrace the unerasable wounds and accept this body.
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Let's go together, nameless monster.
ああ
Ah...
神ハ告ゲル 真ノ世界ヲ
God announces the true world.
黒い鉄格子のなかで
Behind these black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world
悪意の代償を願え
Pray for the cost of malice
望むがままにお前に
To you, just as you wish,
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, let us grant you justice
壊して 壊される前に
Destroy, before being destroyed
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of karma,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
Repay, nameless monster
黒い雨 降らせこの空
Let black rain fall upon this sky
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted creature
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
To the beloved bystanders sharing the same guilt
さあ今ふるえ正義を
Now, exercise justice
消せない傷を抱きしめて
Embracing unerasable scars,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Let's go together, nameless monster
さて、ここからは...
Now then, from here on...
楠木ともりが 鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念グッズをご紹介！
I, Tomori Kusunoki, will introduce Takane Lui's birthday merch!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド
Glitter Acrylic Stand
キラキラなラメ入りアクリルスタンドが、とってもおしゃれな一品
A sparkly glitter acrylic stand that is super stylish.
光を浴びるたびに、きめ細やかなラメがキラキラと輝きを放ちます
Every time it catches the light, fine glitter sparkles brilliantly.
光り輝くアクリルスタンドで、あなたの生活も更に明るくなるでしょう
With this glowing acrylic stand, your daily life will shine even brighter.
ロック風パーカー
Rock-Style Hoodie
イベントやライブで着るだけでなく、日常にも溶け込むロック風パーカー
A rock-style hoodie perfect not just for concerts, but daily life too.
前にジップがついているので、部屋着でも普段着でも使いやすい
With a front zipper, it's easy to wear as loungewear or casual outfits.
ヘビロテ間違いなし！
Guaranteed to be in heavy rotation!
ゆるかわバケットハット
Yurukawa Bucket Hat
つくねとつみれがワンポイントになっていて シンプルおしゃかわ
Tsukune and Tsumire add a cute accent—simple and stylishly adorable.
普段使いしやすいデザインで 手軽におしゃれ度UP
An easy everyday design that effortlessly upgrades your style.
カジュアル、ストリート、古着MIXなど、幅広いスタイルにマッチ
Matches various styles like casual, street, and vintage mix.
「え？」Tシャツ
'Eh?' T-Shirt
ルイ一族でおなじみのセリフ「え？」をモチーフにネタTとして堂々発売
Featuring Lui's famous line 'Eh?' as a joke tee, proudly released!
どんなコーデにも合う白で、夏は単体で、冬はパーカーと合わせて一年中使える
In versatile white, wear it solo in summer or under a hoodie in winter all year.
全部セットは数量限定もアリ！
The full set is also available in limited quantities!
鷹嶺ルイ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード特典
Includes Takane Lui's autographed card with a foil-stamped message!
hololive 公式ECサイトへ急げ！！
Hurry to the official Hololive EC site!!
今だけ！誕生日のフルセット1点購入につき、PRカード1枚プレゼント！
Special offer! Get 1 PR card with each purchase of a full birthday set!
続いては、ミオルイです！
Next up is MioLui!
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
なかなかね、この2人っていうのは珍しいよねー。
It's pretty rare to see these two together, isn't it?
そうですかね？結構ね、お話は...
Is that so? Actually, we talk...
2人仲良いんですよ。/ はい、そうなんです。
We two are actually quite close. / Yes, that's right.
えー、何について話してるの？
Eh, what do you usually talk about?
主に...まあ私がそもそもミオしゃの歌が本当に大好きで...
Mainly... well, first of all, I really love Miosha's singing...
よく歌のお話をしたりとか、あとは個人的に私の悩みに乗ってもらったりとか、してますね。
We often talk about music, and she also listens to my personal worries.
あー、頼りがあるからねー。/ そうなんです！
Ah, because she's so dependable! / That's right!
じゃあその、特別なエピソードとかあったりする？
So, do you have any special stories between you?
特別なエピソードっていうと、私がちょっとしょぼんとした時があったんですけど...
Speaking of special episodes, there was a time when I was feeling down...
素敵だねー。 / 素敵ですねー。
That's so lovely. / It really is.
大神さんはよくお花とか買うの？
Oogami-san, do you often buy flowers?
あ、はい！お花凄い大好きで...
Ah, yes! I really love flowers...
うちも落ち込んだ時とかね、お花を買う時結構あるんですけど...
When I feel down at home, I often buy flowers...
猫が食べちゃうんでね、あんまり買えないんですけどね！
But my cat ends up eating them, so I can't buy them very often!
さっき聞き逃してたけど、君たちもよくパーティーするんだね？
I missed this earlier, but you guys host parties often too, huh?
あ、そうですね！おかゆと同じパーティーですね。
Ah, that's right! It's the same party with Okayu.
私もよく実は参加させていただいております。
Actually, I often get invited to join too.
へっ？さっき隠してたのって...白上くんも参加してるってこと？
Huh? What you were hiding earlier... means Shirakami-kun participates too?
あ、そうですね！ミオさんのオムライスとルイさんのポテトサラダがめちゃくちゃ絶品なんですよ！
Ah, yes! Miosha's omelet rice and Lui-san's potato salad are absolutely divine!
ちょっと収集つかなくなりそうなんで、スタンバイお願いします！
Looks like things are getting out of hand, so please prepare to standby!
はーい！よろしくお願いします！
Okay! Thank you!
またパーティーしようねー！
Let's party again sometime!
何か作ったりしてるの？パーティーで。
Are you making anything for the party?
いや、私は食べる専門ですね。
No, I specialize in eating!
食べる専門...
Specializing in eating...
甘やかされてるね。
You're so spoiled!
そうですね。ポルさんも一度いかがですか？
That's true. Pol-san, why don't you try it once?
うんうん。
Mm-mm.
ポルさんも甘えたいってこと？
You mean you want to be spoiled too, Pol-san?
それはちょっと...
That's a bit...
え？
Eh?
それでは参りましょう！ミオルイで「Beat Eater」！
Now then, let's get started! "Beat Eater" by MioRui!
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
分かってんだ 魅せられたからって
I know, just because I was captivated
雑な罠に嵌まるつもりなど無い
I have no intention of falling into a cheap trap
当たり前が止まんない 怖いな
The ordinary won't stop, it's terrifying
もどかしさも正しい命題
Even impatience is a correct premise
ハロー 湧いてくる束の間の自負心
Hello, a fleeting sense of pride welling up
そこからはどう見えてる？
How does it look from where you are?
tell me, tell me
どれだけ僕を救ってくれるの
How much will you save me?
反響していく声 加速して
Echoing voices, accelerating
始まりは何処から？
Where did it begin?
それも容赦無い力
That too is an unforgiving power
身体を支配している満ち足りた意欲
A satisfying ambition controlling the body
darlin' darlin' タフに噛んでいくスタイル
darlin' darlin', a style of chewing through toughly
まにまに幕を上げるのさ
Raising the curtain as time flows
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
Whatever happens, it's no surprise
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
Increasing momentum, becoming the answer and beginning to echo
come over 消えていかない感覚
come over, a feeling that won't fade away
あくまで踊ってたいだけ
I just want to keep dancing to the end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Damn, even though it's just somehow
見透かされてんのの鬼
It's scary how clearly I'm seen through
予想よりうねって長い傾向
A trend curling longer than expected
不確かなものに用囲まれてんだね
Surrounded by uncertain things, aren't we?
そこらじゅうに転がってる情弱
The info-weak rolling around everywhere
妄想だって思いのほか重要
Delusions are unexpectedly important
心に逆らう外れた振る舞い
Conduct out of line that disobeys the heart
早まったのさ引くに引けない様相
We rushed in, an inescapable situation
ほら手に入れた座標を打ち込め
Look, enter the coordinates you obtained
姿を映してアブラカダブラ
Reflecting the figure, Abracadabra
道は分かれてたんだ
The paths had split apart
それも遠い所から
And from a distant place too
全て間違いじゃない悲しみ方
Not every way of grieving is a mistake
darlin' darlin' 満更でもない
darlin' darlin', not entirely bad either
まにまに塗り直すのさ
Repainting it as time flows
今になればいつだって構わない
Now that it's come to this, anytime is fine
色を変え答えになって溢れ出すよ
Changing colors, becoming the answer and overflowing
come over 消えていかない感覚
come over, a feeling that won't fade away
まだまだ足りてないみたい
It seems it's still not enough
重なり合う光 痛みに寄り添う
Overlapping lights leaning into pain
何処にも消えないで欲しい
I want it to never disappear anywhere
留まる濃い深い重心頼り
Relying on the deep, heavy center of gravity that stays
傷付くこともある
There are times when we get hurt
darlin' darlin' タフに噛んでいくスタイル
darlin' darlin', a style of chewing through toughly
まにまに体現するのさ
Embodying it as time flows
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
Whatever happens, it's no surprise
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
Increasing momentum, becoming the answer and beginning to echo
come over 消えていかない感覚
come over, a feeling that won't fade away
あくまで踊ってたいだけ
I just want to keep dancing to the end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I realized that right now I'm rollin'
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Damn, even though it's just somehow
見透かされてんのの鬼
It's scary how clearly I'm seen through
続いては鷹嶺ルイです。
Next up is Takane Lui.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you for having me.
鷹嶺くんは、最近ハマってるゲームとかあるの？
Takane-kun, do you have any games you're into recently?
ハマってるゲーム、あります！
I do have games I'm into!
最近ってわけでもないんですけど、事務所に入ってから「ドラゴンクエスト」というゲームに出会いまして。
It's not really recent, but after joining the agency, I encountered a game called "Dragon Quest".
あ、ドラゴンクエスト！
Ah, Dragon Quest!
ナンバリング1から11までやっていて、派生とかもあるので、本当に面白くてですね、大好きです。
I've played numbered titles 1 through 11, plus spin-offs, so it's really fun, and I love it.
ドラゴンクエストのどんなところが魅力？
What do you find so appealing about Dragon Quest?
魅力たくさんあるんですけど、本当に人生の教科書だなって思うことが結構多くて。
There are so many appealing points, but I often feel it's truly a textbook of life.
もちろん悲しいこともあるんですけど、それを仲間たちと支え合って前に進んでいくパワーと、
Of course, there are sad moments too, but the power to move forward by supporting each other with companions,
ナンバリングが進んでいくにつれて分かる真実とかがあったりとか、
and the truths you uncover as the series progresses,
長年愛されている理由が詰まってるなって感じますね。
I feel it's packed with the reasons why it's been loved for so many years.
なんかドラクエのそういうイベントとか行ったりしてるの？
Have you been going to Dragon Quest events and stuff like that?
はい、行ってますね。ドラクエのテーマパークだったりとか
Yes, I have. Like Dragon Quest theme parks
あとは限定ショップに行ったりとか
or visiting limited-time pop-up shops,
あとはアニメもあるので、あの、ファンの人と同時視聴とかしたりしてましたね、はい。
and since there's an anime, I've done watch parties with fans and things like that, yes.
充実してんな！
You're really living it up!
充実してます。
It's been very fulfilling.
そんなドラクエ大好きな鷹嶺ルイさんには
For Takane Lui-san, who loves Dragon Quest so much,
これからアニメ『ドラゴンクエスト ダイの大冒険』の初代オープニング『生きるをする』を披露していただきます！
she will now perform "Ikiru o Suru", the first opening theme of the anime Dragon Quest: The Adventure of Dai!
それは楽しみだ！
I'm really looking forward to it!
特別な演出にも注目してくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be thrilled if you also pay attention to the special stage production!
それではスタンバイお願いします！
Alright then, please get ready!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you, here I go!
はまれるものがあるっていうのは、いいよね。
Having something you can get so into is really nice, isn't it?
いいですよね！何やらこの曲を歌ってほしいというリクエストもかなり多かったみたいですよ。
It really is! Apparently, there were a lot of requests for her to sing this song.
あ、ってことは、みんな待望ってわけだね。
Ah, so that means it's highly anticipated by everyone.
ですね！
Indeed!
それではスタンバイができたみたいなので行きましょう！鷹嶺ルイさんで『生きるをする』です。どうぞ！
It looks like she's ready, so let's get into it! Here is Takane Lui with "Ikiru o Suru". Take it away!
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Me loving myself to the very end—
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe in it?
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey takes me,
あれ、いつからだ？ 本音が弱音になったな
Huh, when did it happen? My true feelings turned into weak complaints.
逃げないことが強さになった
Not running away became my strength.
なあ、見つからない？ 自信じゃなく自分自身
Hey, can't you find it? Not confidence, but your true self.
きっとまだ探せてない忘れものがあるはず
There must still be forgotten things I haven't found yet.
ずっとまだ伝えてない伝えたい言葉
Words I've wanted to convey, but haven't said all this time.
見ててくれるなら魅せてみせるのに
If you'll watch me, I'll show you something captivating.
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Me loving myself to the very end—
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe in it?
くすぶるのは、ちゃんと燃えたからだ
Smoldering happens because I burned properly.
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey takes me,
ただ、目を見開いて夢を見る
I'll simply keep my eyes wide open and dream.
夢を知る
I learn what dreams are.
よう、生きてるかい？
Yo, are you living?
本当の強さ きみだけが分かってればいいのさ
True strength—as long as you alone understand it, that's enough.
逃げたり傷ついた数だけ居場所は増えたりする
The places where you belong increase by as many times as you've fled or been hurt.
見ててくれ 姿じゃなく生き方を
Watch me, not my appearance, but the way I live.
僕が僕を愛し抜かなきゃ
I have to love myself to the very end.
終わらない聖者の交信、悲しみの縫い目に投げキッス
An endless communion of saints, blowing a kiss to the seams of sadness.
どこへ向かう旅でも行こうぜ
Whichever direction the journey goes, let's go!
まだ手をとりあって
Still holding hands with each other.
脳、映像、スカイはグレー、夜を駆ける
Brain, images, sky is gray, rushing through the night.
束の間、終幕、裏切りは愛のおまけ
Fleeting moments, the final curtain, betrayal is just an extra to love.
かさぶたになる日々 美しくはないのサ
The days that turn into scabs aren't beautiful.
腰に巻いた正義の切れ味はどんなだ
How sharp is the justice strapped to your waist?
僕らは違う痛みを生きる
We live through different kinds of pain.
勇敢でいたい、立ち向かいたい
I want to be brave, I want to stand up and face it.
眠っていたストーリーを凄いスピードで覚ましたいや
I want to wake up the sleeping story at intense speed.
僕が僕を愛せる強さを
The strength to love myself—
かなり愛してもいいか？
can I love it quite a lot?
くすぶるのだ 燃えカスになるまで
Smolder on until you turn to cinders!
どこへ向かう旅だっていいさ いいのさ
Whatever journey we head on is fine, it's fine.
ただ、目を見開いて息をする
I simply keep my eyes wide open and breathe.
生きるをする
I live my life.
これでもくらえ！
Take this!
続いてはおにかんです。
Next up is Onikan.
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat us well!
前回に引き続きもう、2人は仲が良いね。
Continuing from last time, you two sure get along well.
はい、仲良いですよ。
Yes, we get along very well.
仲良しです。
We're close friends.
息もぴったりだ。
You're in total sync.
なきりさんは、今日シュークリーム食べた？
Nakiri-san, did you eat a cream puff today?
今日はね、まだ食べてないんですよ。でもお弁当食べました！
I haven't eaten one today yet. But I ate a bento!
お弁当ね、美味しいのあったからね。
Right, they had really delicious bentos today.
ね、私達も後で食べましょうね、ポルさん。
Yeah, let's eat later too, Pol-san.
そうね、お腹ペコペコだからね。
Yeah, since I'm totally starving.
えー、そして何やらおふたりは、私達MCに聞きたいことがあるらしいですよ。
And it seems you two have something you want to ask us, the MCs.
いや、こうやってミュージックガーデンやってますけど、おふたりはなんか『歌いたい！』ってなってないですか？
Well, we're doing Music Garden like this, but don't you two feel like "I wanna sing!"?
『歌いてぇ』みたいな。
Like, "I wanna sing!"
歌いてぇ？ まぁ、多少ね。
"Wanna sing?" Well, a little bit.
口ずさんだり身体動いたりするけどね。
We hum along and move our bodies, but...
MCだからね！
We're the MCs, after all!
ほう、じゃあ本当は歌って踊りたいってことでいいですか？
Oh, so does that mean you actually want to sing and dance?
いや、皆さんの良いパフォーマンス見てたらね…
Well, seeing everyone's great performances...
じゃあね、踊って歌いましょうか！
Well then, shall we dance and sing!
はい、じゃあ立っていただいて。
Alright, please stand up.
いいからいいから！立って立って！
Come on, come on! Stand up, stand up!
あっち側で衣装を着替えていただいていいですか？
Could you go over there and change into outfits?
すぐ行く！すぐ行く！
We'll go right away! Right away!
スタンバイしに行ってください！
Please go get on standby!
じゃあね、こちらで一旦CMで…
Well then, over here let's take a short break...
あ、それ私のセリフ！
Ah, that's my line!
準備できたかな？着替えがあったんで着替えましたけども。
I wonder if they're ready? There were outfits, so we changed into them.
じゃあ私達も行きましょうか。
Then shall we go too?
ポルさん、カンペ読んでください！
Pol-san, please read the cue card!
それではお聴きください！おにかん＋フブポルで『チャンカパーナ』！
Now then, please listen! Onikan + FubuPol with "Chankapana"!
深夜バスで君を見た 息を呑むような黒髪
I saw you on the midnight bus, with breath-taking black hair
行き先は違うけれど オレは迷わず飛び乗る
Though our destinations are different, I jump on without hesitation
一人じゃ悲しすぎる夜さ 誰かと話したかった
This night is too lonely alone, I wanted to talk with someone
君もうれしそうで どちらからともなく 手を握る
You look happy too, and without either of us starting it, we hold hands
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts
もう ジンジ 燃えている 身体は止まらない
Burning up inside, my body can't stop
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
頷いた君 抱きしめた
I embraced you as you nodded
恥じらうその瞳 狂ってしまいそう
Those bashful eyes, I feel like I'm going crazy
夜の吐息のなか チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
In the night's breath, Chankapana, Chankapana
バスを捨てて二人は 眠れる場所を探した
Leaving the bus behind, the two of us looked for a place to sleep
うやうやしく服を脱ぎ ベッドに滑り込む花
Reverently undressing, a flower slipping into bed
この世にも天使いたのさ その肌に触れたんだ
There really was an angel in this world, I touched that skin
「恋って好き」なんて悪戯に言うから 舞い上がる
Mischievously saying "I love romance," sending me soaring
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
人生で一番美味しいもの
The most delicious thing in my life
そう ナン ナン 何度だって 君を抱いていたい
Yes, no matter how many times, I want to hold you
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan Chan Chankapana, Chankapana
まだまだ君が足りないよ
I still can't get enough of you
露なその果実 狂ってしまいそう
That exposed fruit, I feel like I'm going crazy
夜よ覚めないでくれ チャンカパーナ
Night, please don't awaken, Chankapana
美しい恋にする
I'll make it a beautiful love
美しい恋にするよ
美しい恋にするから
Because I'll make it a beautiful love
約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise you, Chankapana
美しい恋にするから 約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
"I'll make it a beautiful love, I promise, Chankapana."
月がふたりを探すから
The moon is searching for the two of us,
今夜 世界から身を隠そう
so tonight, let's hide ourselves from the world.
覗いたその肌は 褐色の葡萄だね
That peeked skin of yours is like tan grapes, isn't it?
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan-Chan-Chankapana, Chankapana!
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so badly it hurts.
もう ジンジン 燃えている 身体は止まらない
My body, burning hot, won't stop.
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, Chan-Chan-Chankapana, Chankapana!
オレの腕にしがみついた
You clung to my arms,
華奢なその肩に 狂ってしまいそう
those delicate shoulders drive me crazy.
夜の吐息のなか チャンカパーナ
In the breath of the night, Chankapana.
チャンカパーナ
Chankapana!
ハッハッハッハッハ...
Ha ha ha ha ha...
鷹嶺ルイ生誕3Dライブを見ている諸君、お初にお目にかかる。
To all of you watching Takane Lui's Birthday 3D Live, pleased to meet you.
私はゼロ。黒の騎士団の総帥にして、世界への反逆者。
I am Zero. Commander of the Black Knights, and rebel against the world.
ここまでのMGAではどうだったかな？ 大いに盛り上がったことだろう。
How was the MGA up to this point? I am sure you were greatly excited.
フッ... だが、まだ足りないな。
Heh... But it is still not enough.
諸君らなら、まだまだ盛り上がれるはずだ！ 鷹嶺ルイの歌によってな！
You all should be able to get much more excited! Through Takane Lui's singing!
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニアが命じる！ 鷹嶺ルイよ、コードギアスの主題歌メドレーで...
Lelouch vi Britannia commands you! Takane Lui, with a Code Geass theme song medley...
さらに盛り上げるのだ！
...excite them even more!
Yes, Your Highness!
コードギアス 反逆のルルーシュ
[Title: Code Geass: Lelouch of the Rebellion]
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
The moment that seems capable of changing myself, even the world,
瞬間は いつもすぐそばに...
...is always right by my side...
隠せぬ苛立ちと 立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Gazing at my unhidable frustration and myself standing frozen,
迷いながら 悩みながら 悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
while wavering, worrying, and regretting, it's fine to decide.
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ 戸惑いは消え去り
With a single word you gave me, confusion fades away,
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
and light shone into my empty room.
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
The vast sky I looked up at clears into a brilliant blue.
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
I decided to open the closed window.
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
The moment that seems capable of changing myself, even the world,
瞬間は いつもすぐそばに...
...is always right by my side...
夢見てた、夢
The dream I was dreaming...
果て無き遠く
...endlessly far away,
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
the sky-blue of dry days in my hands.
乾いた日々の 空色 手の中
The sky color of dry days in my hands
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Trial and error amidst sounds at equal intervals
時間・間隔の無い空間 ah
A space with no time or intervals, ah
等身大 音をたてて
Life-sized, making a noise
僕の顔、造って行く
I go on constructing my face
キレイに、片方だけ。
Beautifully, but only on one side.
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Though I walk a beastly path, roaring like a lion or tiger
茜射す空の 彼方にはまほろば
Beyond the madder-red sky lies a paradise
幽囚の孤独に 彷徨う青春は
Youth wandering in imprisoned solitude
弱さと怒りが 姿なき敵ですか
Are weakness and anger the unseen enemy?
父よ 未だ我は 己を知りがたし
Father, I still find it hard to know myself
先立つ兄らの
Of my departed brothers...
見えない背中を追えば
If I chase their unseen backs
迷いの一夜に 明星は誘う
On a night of hesitation, the morning star beckons
死して終われぬ 夢を焦がれども
Though longing for dreams that do not end with death
確かな君こそ我が命
Certain as you are, you are my life
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Living as a butterfly or flower in the gale-swept wilderness
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
An illusion blooming alongside eternal spring
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Purity amidst turbidity, though this body be sullied
心の錦を信じていてください
Please keep believing in the brocade of my heart
母よ 決して我は 涙を見せねども
Mother, though I never show my tears
足下の草に露は消え模せで
Let not the dew vanish on the grass beneath my feet
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
Yearning morning and night
星になるよ 君守る
I'll become a star to protect you
戦いは行方
Where the battle leads...
シュヴァルツ 明日の
Schwarz, tomorrow's...
王の交差点で
At the king's intersection
交わらない キミとボク
You and I, never intersecting
今行くよボクは流れ星
I'm coming now, I'm a shooting star
世界が朽ち果てても 変わることのないものがある
Even if the world decays, there are things that never change
涙をごらえてでも 守るべきものが僕らにはある
Even holding back tears, there are things we must protect
何万年何億年前からのメッセージが体内であずきだす 鳴り響く
A message from ages ago aches within my body, echoing loud
しゃがれた声で 明日を呼ぶ 傷だらけの手で 君守る
Calling out for tomorrow in a husky voice, protecting you with wounded hands
I continue to fight I continue to fight
見つめ合い 手と手を重ねて ガラス越しのキミとボク
Gazing at each other, overlapping hands, you and I through the glass
こんなにも側にいるのに
Even though we're so close to each other
暗い闇を真っ白に染めるよ
Dyeing the dark night pure white
出口のない 君のもとへ
To you, who have no way out
運命を切り裂く流れ星
A shooting star tearing through fate
あふれる君の涙 ボクがいま奪い去る
Your overflowing tears, I will sweep them away now
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Mosaic pieces, connecting them one by one to draw
あなたがくれた 出会いと別れも
Even the encounters and partings you gave me
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
It shouldn't be like this, thinking so as I sleep
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Waking up to the same old, unchanging spin-wheels
意味も無く繰り返し
Repeating without meaning
モザイクカケラ 拾い集めてた「上手く生きる為の術」
Mosaic pieces, gathering "the art of living well"
歪なそれが美しく見えたんだ
That distorted thing looked beautiful to me
強がりながら 躓きながら選び抜いた道の上で
Bluffing along, stumbling along, on the path I chose
剥がれ落ちては 埋まらないカケラ
Peeling off and falling, pieces that won't fill in
Unfillable pieces peel and fall away...
鷹嶺ルイ コードギアスシリーズ宣伝アンバサダー就任決定
[Takane Lui Appointed as Code Geass Series Promotion Ambassador]
詳細は公式XまたはYouTubeチャンネルで
[Details on Official X or YouTube Channel]
はい、ということで特報VTR見ていただきましたけれども
Alright, so you just watched the special news video...
なんとこの鷹嶺ルイ、なんと！なんと！コードギアスアンバサダーに決定いたしました！
...and Takane Lui has been appointed as the Code Geass Series Ambassador!
やったー！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
私、めちゃくちゃコードギアスシリーズ大、大、大好きなので
I love, love, love the Code Geass series so much,
こんな素晴らしい機会をいただけるの、本当に嬉しいでございます
so I'm truly thrilled to be given such a wonderful opportunity.
皆さんの応援のおかげです！本当にありがとうございます！
It's all thanks to your support! Thank you so much!
そしてですね、皆さんお気づき...もうお気づきですよね？
And also, everyone... you've probably noticed already, right?
もうなんと！ルルーシュ役の福山さんが...
Believe it or not, Mr. Fukuyama, the voice of Lelouch...
「鷹嶺ルイ」と呼んでいただき、演じていただきました！
...called out "Takane Lui" and acted in character for me!
本当にすごい！こんな豪華なことってあるんですか！？
That's incredible! How can something be so lavish?!
いや、本当にありがとうございます！
Really, thank you so much!
もうコードギアスメドレーでもね、あのバックに...
Even during the Code Geass medley,
コードギアスのアニメーションも、歴代のエンディングとオープニングも流れたということで...
we had Code Geass anime visuals, along with iconic theme songs, playing in the background...
本当に豪華な仕上がりになっていたんですけれども...
It turned out so amazingly extravagant...
いかがでしたか、皆さん？
How did you like it, everyone?
ね、はい！私、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！本当にありがとうございます！
Yeah! I'm just so ridiculously happy! Thank you all so much!
アンバサダーとしてのですね、お仕事はですね
As for my duties as ambassador...
「歌ってみた」を上げたりとか、あとは同時視聴をしたりとか
...I'll be posting song covers, hosting watch parties...
あとはそのほか諸々、色々盛りだくさんで用意しておりますので
...and plenty of other exciting things, so stay tuned!
詳細はですね、この後コードギアスシリーズの公式YouTubeチャンネルにも投稿されますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください
Details will be posted shortly on the official Code Geass YouTube channel, so please be sure to check it out!
もちろん私のXでも、XやYouTubeチャンネルでも詳細をその都度伝えていきますので
Of course, I'll also be sharing updates on my X account and YouTube channel as they come,
チャンネル登録、そしてXのフォローもよろしくお願いします
so please subscribe and follow me on X as well!
さて、この後はですね、新曲をお披露目させていただきます！
Now then, next up, I'll be performing my new song!
よっ！来ましたよ、私の新曲が！
Here it comes, my brand new song!
ということで新曲のタイトルはですね...
And the title of this new track is...
「ZIG-ZAG」という曲になっております
...'ZIG-ZAG'!
「ZIG-ZAG」というのはですね、トラウマの別称になっているんですけれども
'ZIG-ZAG' is actually another term for trauma,
そのジグザグ、自分の中にあるトラウマと戦って、格好よく前を向いていくという曲になっておりますので
and it's a song about facing the trauma within yourself and moving forward with style.
ぜひぜひみんなにもちょっと聴いていただいて、「あ、こんなことあるな、私もこんなことあるな」と共感していただけたら嬉しいなと思います
I hope you'll listen to it and relate, thinking, "Yeah, I've felt like this too."
それでは、じゃあ曲振りは...コードギアスのアンバサダーにもなったということで
So, for the song intro... since I've become a Code Geass ambassador,
久々に「ルイ・シュ」でいきたいと思います！
I'll do it as "Lui-louch" for the first time in a while!
みんな、準備はいいか？
Everyone, are you ready?
私の準備もいいか？大丈夫か？
Is my prep good too? All good?
ということで行きますよ！
Alright, here we go!
ルイ・シュ・タカネリアが命ずる！
Lui-louch vi Takaneria commands you!
お前たち、新曲を聴けー！
All of you, listen to my new song!
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four
「幸せ」って囁いた問いが ラッタタラッタ
The whispered question of "happiness", rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
こびり着いて離れぬわ 駄目だ ラッタタラッタ
Sticks to me and won't leave, it's no good, rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember a flavorless, odorless life anymore
忘れたいから歌った 馬鹿だ ラッタタラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, how foolish, rat-ta-ta-rat-ta
恨む事も 憎む事も 賢くない故 出来なかった
Neither holding grudges nor hating was possible, for I wasn't smart enough
これが君の結末ならば 笑ってしまいたいほど
If this is your conclusion, it's almost laughable...
嘘 嘘 嘘
Lies, lies, lies...
「嘘つき」
"Liar."
やだ 痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No way, it hurts, hurts, hurts, foolishly hoping for a miracle
もう 嫌嫌嫌嫌！ タチが悪いわ
Ugh, I hate it, hate it, hate it! It's so nasty
ねぇ 辛い Lie Lie Lie Lie な？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, it's a painful Lie Lie Lie Lie, right? Gouge out all the broken parts
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless if you like, call me whatever you want
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です で・で・です
I just want to say bye-bye to my trauma, I do, I do, I really do
私、甘え上手になれなかった 可愛げとかが足りなかった
I couldn't be good at leaning on others, I lacked sweetness and charm.
後悔が煩い夜だ
It's a night loud with regret.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば？ きっといいコトあるさ とか
What if I just accept that the past is the past? "Good things will come" and all that...
それくらい 百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I know all of that full well, rat-tat-ta.
願う事も 祈る事も 許されないから黒く染めた
I wasn't allowed to wish or pray, so I dyed it black.
元の色も思い出せない 絡んだ運命の
I can't even recall the original color, this tangled fate's...
糸 糸 糸 糸
threads, threads, threads, threads.
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い な 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, so cringey, cringey, playing the tragic heroine like this.
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 諦めてちゃえば？
Enough, no, no, no, why not just give up?
でも 会いたい たい たい だな 思考回路がこんがらかっちゃって
But I wanna, wanna, wanna see you, my thoughts are all tangled up.
明日またきっと 壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's fine.
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです です で・で・です
Even my trauma is precious to me, yes, y-y-yes.
夢の中で君と 手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I'm holding hands with you.
何も知らないあの頃の 二人のままで
Just like back then, when the two of us knew nothing.
でもわかっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know I'll wake up soon enough.
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと
If so, then I'd rather you finish me off softly with your hands,
止め刺して ほら 今 今 今！
come on, right now, now, now!
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い な 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
Ugh, so pathetic, actually hoping for a miracle.
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タチが悪いわ
Enough, no, no, no, it's such a bad habit.
ねぇ 辛い Lie Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, painful Lie Lie Lie Lie, no? Gouge out everything wrong with me.
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless if you want, call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です で・で・です
I just want to say bye-bye to my trauma, yes, y-y-yes.
嘘つき...
Liar...
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛い な 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
Ugh, so pathetic, actually hoping for a miracle,
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タチが悪いわ
enough, no, no, no, it's such a bad habit.
ねぇ 辛い Lie Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, painful Lie Lie Lie Lie, no? Gouge out everything wrong with me.
楽しくお届けしてきましたMUSIC GARDEN
We've been happily bringing you MUSIC GARDEN,
あっという間にエンディングのお時間となりましたー！ ポルさん、今日はどうでしたかー？
and it's already time for the ending! Pol-san, how was it today?
いやー、なんか今日は私も一緒に歌って踊っちゃったからね！
Man, since I sang and danced along today too,
いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったねー！
the hype was even higher than usual!
あー、あと、もう一時間...
Ah, also, just one more hour...
いや、やらないですけど。本当はもっとやりたいんですけどね
No, we're not doing that, though we'd love to do more!
グッズ販売とプレミア公開も待ってますので！
We also have merch sales and the premiere release coming up!
あー、そっかそっか！
Ah, right, right!
いや、鷹嶺くん、今日はてんこ盛りだったね！
Man, Takane-kun, today was absolutely packed!
まさか... コードギアス...
I mean... Code Geass...
溜めてる、溜めてる！
Building up the suspense, building it up!
私もね、早く言いたくて言いたくてたまらなかったです
I couldn't wait to tell everyone about it!
このあとグッズ販売と新曲プレミア公開、そしてメンバーシップ限定配信もありますので
After this, we have merch sales, a new song premiere, and a member-exclusive stream,
楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです！
so I hope you'll enjoy them!
本当にこのあとも盛りだくさんだ！
There really is so much more coming up!
改めて、お誕生日おめでとうね！
Once again, happy birthday!
MUSIC GARDEN 2ができて本当に嬉しいです
I'm so happy we could do MUSIC GARDEN 2!
ポルさんもフブさんも本当にありがとうございました！
Pol-san, Fubu-san, thank you both so much!
ぜひね、またやりたいね！
We definitely want to do this again!
まあぜひまたやりたいですね！
Yes, we'd absolutely love to!
せっかくですので、ゲストの皆さんにも感想いただきましょう！
Since everyone is here, let's hear from our guests!
皆さんから何か言いたいことがあるみたいですよー！
Looks like they have something to say to you!
ルイ！
Lui!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！ みんなと歌えて幸せでした！
Thank you so much! I was so happy singing with everyone!
またコラボしよう！ - ぜひしようー！
Let's collab again! - Definitely!
はい！ では本当にあっという間ですが
Alright! Time really flew by,
今夜のMUSIC GARDENはここまでとなります！ ありがとうございましたー！
but that's all for tonight's MUSIC GARDEN! Thank you so much!
それではまた、MUSIC GARDEN 3が叶う日まで... さようなら！
Until the day MUSIC GARDEN 3 comes true... goodbye!
さようならー！
Goodbye!
ラプ、やべーぞ！
Lap, this is crazy!
どうしたー？
What's wrong?
とんでもねーグッズ出るぞ！
Some incredible merch is coming out!
はい？
Huh?
バカすげーグッズが一気に来るぞ！
A crazy amount of awesome merch is dropping all at once!
Tシャツ！
T-shirt!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド！
Glitter acrylic stand!
ゆるかわバケットハット！
Cute & casual bucket hat!
欲し〜え！
I want it!
ロック風パーカー！
Rock-style hoodie!
着たーい！
I wanna wear it!
そして...
And...
直筆サイン入りポストカードが付くぞ！
It comes with an autographed postcard!
な、なんだってー！？
Wh-What?!
さらにホロカもついてくる！
Plus, it comes with a HoloKa card!
うわー！
Whoa!
これは買いでしょう！
This is a total must-buy!